why did i start my episode here
of all places well i know what you've
all been waiting for in this episode of
hermitcraft it's something magnificent
something exciting something so
brilliant and dastardly and okay it's my
sugarcane farm it's really not that
exciting but i genuinely need to finish
this and i've been putting it off i've
done a little bit of work so i thought
i'd kick off this episode
with a little bit of chores i'm not
gonna lie but what this did actually
make me realize is under here without
all of these torches this place spawned
instantly 100 mobs meaning that this
area is also going to be good for a mob
farm
but either way i've really got to finish
this so i think we're gonna try and kick
off today's episode with the most
exciting thing ever
yay
rails and collection systems
let's let's just get this done really
quickly
[Music]
it's 100
not the most efficient thing in the
world but i couldn't feel proud of this
because it's the first time i've
actually done something by myself
completely i obviously knew how the
flying machine works because mumbo makes
these frequently i kind of i kind of
memorized that whole thing but
everything else was kind of on me i feel
pretty confident and i actually figured
out a really cool way to know when it's
time for this thing to harvest
automatically so i've just got one bit
of sugar cane over here and when it
grows
to where the observer is and i'm kind of
just hoping that it's going to grow
any second
now okay we might have to wait tick-tock
i haven't got all day
any second now
any second
now come on stupid sugarcane i've
officially been here five minutes now
waiting for the grass to grow what a
riveting start to today's episode i told
you this is the story everyone's been
waiting for green to finish his
sugarcane farm no seriously this is
taking the mick now i think i might have
just proved my entire
concept
wrong you see
most of this
is ready i think we're only seconds away
from this whole thing needing to be
completely torn down and harvested
but this little guy doesn't want to move
why has this episode suddenly become a
saga about me
waiting for this stupid sugar cane to
grow
come on grow grow grow grow grow i'm not
taking my eyes off this because if i
miss this i'm gonna be furious
are we gonna have to why we have to do
the grow dance come on grow sugarcane
grow sugarcane this sugarcane's driving
me insane i'm losing my
mind grow
i've been waiting 15 minutes everything
else okay there are a few left that
haven't grown to a full capacity
but it all rides on this guy yeah the
sugarcane's gonna grow it's gonna grow
sometime soon i don't have things to do
i don't have an episode to make it's
cool it's cool holding me up
there was me thinking i've been
innovative i've been creative
and other ifs but this
is not working maybe maybe i maybe i
need to stop looking at it maybe it's
just a bit shy
it hasn't been half an hour it's just
been a really long time
so maybe i just need to turn my back and
it'll grow
i just can't can't look at it it's just
a shy grower that's fine i see i see the
others sugarcane look that's growing
that's fine so if i just don't look i
might catch it i didn't really expect
this episode to become a war between
myself
and a single piece of sugarcane
yet here we are maybe i can startle it
forget it
at some point we gotta we gotta cut our
losses
it must it demands blood
it demands blood
what do you want from me
sugar cane
i think we now know the answer who would
win in a fight
one minecraft buildy boy
or one sugarcane
oh i did it yeah i missed it no
no
[Laughter]
but yes
it worked okay we should start seeing
all this sugarcane
vanishing
in front of our eyes as the minecarts
pick it all up as it goes back and forth
underneath the system then this comes
back it sets itself in there and then it
waits for the whole thing to reset so
it's going to take a while for all of
these to go
because it's got to make a couple of
trips i can't believe after all that i
missed it so if we look under here this
is my collection system and it is
depositing all of the sugarcane
in the hopper system so really awesome
stuff this is probably not the best
redstone in the world but hey
i made it and that makes it all the more
satisfying i must admit i'm suddenly
really getting it like i understand how
this works because of the item sorter
system and i figured i could just make a
bunch of them and link them all up
and we end up with a whole bunch of junk
as well where did all this come from so
we got lots of sugarcane which is
exactly what we want so i would call
this an immediate success we're not
gonna stop and watch it go again because
that was awful what we are gonna do is
head over to the shopping district where
we've got to check
on some of our barge mystery treasure
hunt boxes still needs a better name in
my opinion is still still a bit of a
mouthful so let's see how we've done did
we get any okay we've sold out
that was quick
it's only been a couple of days and
they're all
gone well
i can't keep up
if this is it
i don't know i
i don't know what to do i'll leave a
review board here so people can leave
what they think and we can get feedback
and improve the mystery barge box and so
next time it's going to be more
expensive and even more elaborate and
insane although
every time i have to reset they sell out
quicker and they take longer to make so
it's difficult oh that i totally forgot
look at all those
look at the diamonds we got dvdb
diamonds diamonds
diamonds
[Music]
diamonds good luck remixing that one oh
my goodness 55 diamond blocks if we add
this to our ever increasing pile of
diamonds we are almost as rich as the
town hall
look at that one two three four stacks
of diamond blocks plus 24 we are rolling
in it what's that spider diamond well
okay then i don't know if people have
actually found their
nope this is one of the this is one of
the prizes so whoever got this one
hasn't actually made it here yet look
there's a logs there's fireworks golden
carrots and then i actually put in a
decked out box as well because i thought
that would be quite a cool prize and
then yeah you win the best reward
so it looks like people bought the boxes
and haven't done them yet oh my goodness
whoa whoa whoa whoa there's another one
what's what's up with all these spider
diamonds my barge is crawling in
diamonds well it's true i got 20 29
diamonds
so that was a success and we'll probably
figure out what we're gonna do
later on did i just see mumbo's face
i think i saw mumbo's face
oh yeah his real face sorry
what
joy in the resistance i guys i told you
mumbo was the leader of the resistance
if that isn't proof i don't know what is
that's insane who's done this that's
hilarious
so now it's time for me to go over
to the mycelium hq
and start working on our base
there we go and we are in our mycelium
resistance headquarters
so it's actually been a few days since
i've been in here so we should check out
if anything's changed what the team's
been up to and it looks like we've been
collecting a fair amount of mycelium and
what about the rooms
nothing here and oh
oh my
that is a violently red room i am not
entirely sure what this is but i'm gonna
guess this is the work of a mad
scientist i mean this room is screaming
mad scientist at me so there's been an
awful lot of suspicious activity and i
have been playing a bit of among us so
i'm extra suspicious of everyone
especially especially etho like we
played among us on my second channel and
he was he was he was so sus so what i
thought i'd add in honor of a bit of
among us
is
a panic button so i just need to make
myself an armor stand what i'm thinking
is we have an armor stand i haven't done
one of these tricks in a while so we
have like this red cap on top of an
armor stand in there and that is our
panic button but i just need to remember
how to make armor stands understands one
of those things that you just constantly
forget about really there we go arm
stand we put in the armor stand and then
we gotta we gotta push it down right we
gotta push down the block
that's it that's how that's how you do
it and you push down the glass block
boom okay that's not layered
particularly well uh
doesn't really i think that needs to be
a bit lower which means
i need snow or to just remove okay i
need snow i need layered snow
do you know what there's actually not a
oh
oh my goodness uh
intrude panic panic button stress isn't
on this team um
um
oh
uh oh goodness okay we can't let her
leave we got she's found the entrance
she's found the secret entrance
um
uh
can i
call you one sec
oh i'm gonna have to black this this is
like a
this is like a game of among us no dear
hi stress
hi um you got green yeah
um i what
where am i
you are in
the mycelium resistance headquarters
which you definitely didn't find the
entrance to
i
i i literally
i was up in the shopping center
okay so so so so i'm glad you're here
because i would love to have you on the
mycelium resistance if you're interested
uh you've i mean you this it was a test
it was all a test you found the entrance
so
uh if you want to join i am all up for
it you've proven yourself um thanks so
much
now that you're inducted in the mycelium
resistance um rule number one is never
show the location of the entrance you
just found never never speak of it never
show it if you if you were recording
that i'm gonna need you to like delete
that bit or cut that out oh my god okay
so you're now an official mycelium
resistance member you have no choice
because you found our secret oh
this is so weird i'm not gonna lie
literally i don't even know what just
happened
okay well i suppose
yes
then excellent choice it's not a
disaster okay
okay brilliant i'm gonna give you a new
role i'm gonna give you a roll in the
resistance you
definitely didn't catch me by surprise
just then i was in the middle of making
a panic button yeah and then i started
to panic
well literally i just i literally just
fell
no no no no details no details okay i'm
sorry
sorry sorry i'm sorry okay so if you
want to come and have a look these are
the members of the mycelium resistance
you're now sworn to secrecy
oh gold okay
so
i'm mother sports so my job is to look
after all the other spallings
you are going to be
head of investigation
all you got to do is find out what the
the hip are up to okay
hip yeah so okay right if you go if you
watch scars video right he's made hep
the herman hermit environmental
protection agency right okay all right
it's called hep that is that spells hep
but he calls it hip so i've started
calling it yep
okay all right
okay so i have to like spy on them yeah
you're just you're investigating you're
just you know
finding out what they're up to just
chilling
yeah they're making their base about the
same time as we're making ours so it's
it's starting to ramp up so i'm kind of
glad that you're here because we were
slightly outnumbered
oh okay well i'm glad that um i dropped
in
um okay thank goodness we just made a
panic button because i was full on
panicking we have just thoroughly been
rumbled
i didn't even see her drop in
but i think
just like among us i smoothed it over
with a little bit of blagging
and we've got ourselves an additional
member to the resistance
i don't know what i would have done if
she said no if she had if she had
declined and gone to the other side our
base all our efforts to conceal the
entrance to the base would have been for
nothing
okay well now i feel like we really do
need a panic button we really do need a
panic button maybe maybe this base isn't
as well hidden as i would like seeing as
someone literally just dropped in on me
emergency meeting okay i i'm kind of
hoping i might ask etho if he can make a
button that actually gives us an
emergency meeting song that'd be cool
now that that is taken care of we can
start working on actually spreading some
mycelium and actually doing what we set
out to do which is resist
but my idea for this isn't quite as
simple as it might seem because
and if you don't know minecraft too well
nothing spawns on the mycelium island
in that biome the only thing that spawns
is nothing including the cows which is
why we need to go on a bit of a hunt for
some sheep which i didn't really expect
to have to do in today's episode you
know what there's a lot of unexpected
things we're doing in today's episode
sugarcane and sheep
that is that is what we've been doing
today i've just realized an enormous
flaw in my plan how do i get these two
into the mycelium resistance hq ah it's
not gonna be easy we'll figure that out
later the first thing we gotta do is get
these two
in
not in the same boat
sheep delivery what's up guys
it's me
sheep my neck's broken oh man that was a
seriously painful journey and it was
only one out of two
sheep number two you're coming with me
your head is even more broken than the
last one
you're perfect
i need another sheep first of all let's
name these guys so they're not going
anywhere agent zero and agent one
i think you guys you need a better
disguise than just sheep if you ask me
much better
much
agent zero agent one
let's have that wool
is perfect
okay so
let's make sure that my plan works
they've even got little earpieces that
is magnificent okay so the plan is
you two are going to transform the
island for us
for us
and just to make sure that my plan works
we're going to set this all up
so this entire theory works on minecraft
mechanics
so all we got to do is get a sheep in
this pen so here's the plan
we place down a mycelium now in theory
the sheep won't eat the mycelium but
they will eat the grass so if we just
wait here and watch what happens
over time we should see mycelium spread
more than grass so
let's just wait and see
[Music]
okay so
that was a very quick time lapse and
that was three hours of footage i'm not
kidding
three hours i sat here looking at grass
grow
first we
watched the sugar cane grow and then we
watched the mycelium spread however
what i did was like every now and again
i realized this wasn't working and then
i bred a few more sheep from agents zero
and one
and
before you knew it four sheep seemed to
be enough to change it in just 10
minutes so
i've been breeding a lot of sheep up and
the reason
is to make the process a lot faster so
if we create an army of agents ready to
go we can send them up we can add whoa
what is it with being spooked i thought
we'd just been rumbled again we'll send
them up we'll put some mycelium down and
what does impulse want i think the hepa
having a meeting right now
oh snap
put your game face on then by game face
yes
yes okay i'm gonna call him now let's go
let's go let's go let's go okay let's go
let's go let's go let's go let's go
we gotta get there before they're here
let's go go to the hip building
they're here
i decided to call it pep because or hip
because it's clearly called hep but scar
calls it hip oh dude i'm totally in
there oh dude how okay okay
uh-huh okay now we gotta land
without being seen this is not going to
happen is it
no they're going to see us we have to
shift immediately are you landing right
on top yep
okay okay okay okay okay i think i can i
can land shifted right yes okay
i'm right on top of the building oh
they're right under me i don't know well
i don't know what we can gain from this
other than knowing okay oh wait no dude
dude we son we know who's in
the heap
yeah tango x scar a cub and
someone else was there
was it false i thought i saw false there
it is
we got some info do you think they heard
us land oh definitely oh corrales is in
there too oh for real dude he was
crouching a long time
i cuz i think they might have heard us
land maybe potentially
oh no
i'm afraid to stop shifting i think they
haven't come out they haven't so
here if we need to make a quick escape
we could use this okay just went and had
a look oh yeah
yeah yeah we could totally under pearl
away
oh man okay we just got some valuable
information that's super good
information dude tango's on their team
i'm sorry i haven't seen any of these
guys
they've been recruiting they have been
recruiting i think we take the
information and we just get out of here
without being seen
whoa who do you
know awkward
oh i'm at the bottom of the ocean they
didn't see me
oh no
you got busted me dude
that was the worst timing we got to come
up with something quick
i was
just looking for decked out boxes
nothing to see here
i mean i can't argue with that we're
always around the shopping district i
don't think they're buying your story
though they didn't know by my story oh
red okay all right well hey we i think
it was still profitable
just to have that information still a
good thing super super good so that was
pretty informative we better take our
game face off
the face of the resistance is beat ups
so we need to head back to the mycelium
resistance hq
and get cracking on the rest of the
build so we've got some
major advancements in the form of many
many sheep before i got interrupted by
this sign and i think what we need to do
is reevaluate how we tackle
spreading the mycelium
so i think we need to put down just a
few blocks here and there and then let
loose more sheep than they could ever
handle and it looks like ren has already
provided a method to get the mobs up to
the shopping district but for now i
think that's probably
those sheep are so cool i think that's
probably enough
of mycelium resistance today we've done
an extreme amount of work check it out i
also while i was off camera
finished this side of
the corridors so that everyone has a
room for whatever we need to do whether
it's farming storage because the storage
problem is actually real like we've got
just boxes of mycelium around and don't
know what to do with it
so i think that is the end of the
episode that is all we have time for
today actually we got a lot done a lot
done whether it was just watching
sugarcane grow or watching mycelium grow
we got a lot done and we've inducted a
new member into the resistance who is
this
corrales
so i hope you enjoyed this video and i
shall see you in the next one where more
shenanigans related to the purple block
are undoubtedly on their way
good bye